Houssem Marzougui

3837 Midgard Pl, Victoria, BC, CA 778-318-7601

marzouguih86@gmail.com

https://github.com/zoug86

6 **(7)** 5 **m**

https://www.linkedin.com/in/houssem-marzougui-0424a795

https://marzougui-h.dev

Summary – Results-driven, self-motivated and hard-working **Frontend web developer** with 10 years of work experience seeking a full-time position in an engineering and professional innovation environment which offers key participation, team-oriented tasks, immediate challenges, and career opportunity.

Professional Attributes

- Fast learner with a strong desire to master new concepts and technologies.
- Have an interest in crafting efficient and scalable modern software solutions.
- Exceptional interpersonal and collaboration skills.
- Strong capacity to work under stress and time constraint.
- Strong leadership and management background.

Skills

- HTML5, CSS3, Material UI, Bootstrap
- JavaScript (ES6), Python
- React.js, Next.js, Redux
- MongoDB, MySQL, Strapi
- Node.js, Express.js, EJS

- Jest, Enzyme, Mocha, Chai testing
- Version Control (Git), GitHub
- Heroku, Netlify, Firebase and Vercel deployment
- REST API, Postman, Docker (basic), Bash
- OOP, Data Structures and Algorithms

Education

Master of Science in Electrical and Computer Engineering

2017-2020

University of Victoria

♥ Victoria, BC, Canada

Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering

2007-2011

United States Naval Academy

Annapolis, MD, USA

Experience

Frontend Developer

Freelance

10/2020 - Present

Developed and designed several client and personal client-side static pages and full stack web applications:

- Portfolio: Personal website built with React. is and Material-Ui and features most projects built to date.
- MCTA: A tutoring website built with *JavaScript and Bootstrap* that offers students different tutoring methods with an onsite PayPal payment option.
- <u>Digi-Thrifting</u>: A *MERN* e-commerce application that offers a collection of electronics with cheap prices: We guarantee the best prices on the market!
- <u>Devcamper</u>: A backend API built with *Express.js and MongoDB* to manage coding bootcamps, courses, reviews, users and authentication.
- <u>DJ-Events</u>: Full-Stack website built with *Next.js and MySQL* that allows users to check on upcoming DJ events uploaded by authenticated users.
- <u>CodeFever</u>: Personal Blog built with *Next.js and Tailwind* that features all the programming and tech tools I am most passionate about.
- <u>GameDB</u>: A gaming application built with *React.js, Styled Components and Framer Motion* that displays all you need to know about existent and upcoming video games.
- <u>Chat-with-React</u>: A chat application built with React.js, Node.js and Socket.io that enables room users to group chat.

Remote Moderator

OneClass | 9 Toronto, ON, Canada 08/2018 – Present

- Supervise and moderate platform educators to ensure highest quality service to students in North America.
- Engage undergraduate students across Canada and the U.S understand their math, computer science, and engineering learning objectives through extensive project assignments.

Technical Analyst

Deloitte | **♥** Kitchener, ON, Canada 01/2019 – 11/2019

- Produced and partially managed Scientific Research and Experimental Development (SR&ED) technical reports for clients in many industries including TMT and Manufacturing in English and French in a rapid and challenging work environment.
- Discussed and studied clients full design engineering projects to determine their innovation levels and SR&ED eligibility.

Research and Teaching Assistant

University of Victoria | ♥ Victoria, BC, Canada 09/2017 – 04/2020

 Implemented and simulated medical ultrasound imaging algorithms in Matlab using adaptive and conventional plane wave compounding techniques that reduced computational complexity and maintained similar image quality.

Software Engineer

The Naval Electronics Division | ♥ Tunis, Tunisia 02/2016 – 02/2017

- Developed a technical report and messaging application to help mechanical engineers on warships get instant feedback on different mechanical and electrical complicated issues built with JS, Node.js, Socket.io and MongoDB.
- Developed a web application that allows logistics officers instant material purchase and stock availability check built with React.js, Node.js and PostgreSQL.

Communications Officer

Tunisian Navy | ♥ Tunis, Tunisia 06/2011 – 01/2016

- Developed and supervised maintenance planning for all transmission Radio equipment onboard naval units to ensure full operational status of different communication systems.
- Developed and conducted training sessions for communication team members.

Publications

• H. Marzougui and D. Rakhmatov, "Data-Driven Sensor Array Subsampling for Plane-Wave Ultrasound Imaging," 2019 IEEE International Ultrasonics Symposium (IUS), Glasgow, United Kingdom, 2019, pp. 2337-2340, doi: 10.1109/ULTSYM.2019.8925560.

Interests

Technology, hiking, cooking, crypto mining, health and wellness

Languages

English (Fluent) - French (Fluent) - Arabic (Native)

References

- Amy San Miguel, Team Leader and Tax Manager, Gi3, Deloitte, 519-650-7820, asanmiguel@deloitte.ca
- Dr. Daler Rakhmatov, Graduate Supervisor, University of Victoria, 250-472-5214, daler@ece.uvic.ca